Finding Aid for [Ann Arbor Planning Commission publications, 1956-2003]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
[Ann Arbor Planning Commission publications] 1956-2003
Ann Arbor (Mich.). Planning Commission.
5 linear feet
4150 Aa 2
Publications of the Ann Arbor Planning Commission including annual reports, capital improvement budgets, and planning studies and reports.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Planning Commission publications have been received in multiple accessions from several donors.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Ann Arbor Planning Commission is a unit of Ann Arbor city government.
Publications of the Ann Arbor Planning Commission, ca. 1961-1997, including annual reports, capital improvement budgets, and planning studies and reports.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Population.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Statistics.; Ann Arbor (Mich.). Planning Commission.; Ann Arbor (Mich.). City Planning Dept.; City planning--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Parks--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Recreation--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Serials
  - Annual report
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - 1976 (Box 1)
    - 1977 (Box 1)
  - Capital improvements budget and program
    - 1960-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1971 (Box 1)
      (General development plan)
    - 1966-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1974 (Box 1)
    - 1969-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1976 (Box 1)
    - 1971-1977 (Box 1)
      (draft)
    - 1972-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1980 (Box 1)
      (draft, October, 1974)
    - 1975/1980 (Box 1)
      (draft, November, 1974)
    - 1975-1980 (Box 1)
    - 1976/1981 (Box 1)
      (draft, October, 1975)
    - 1976-1981 (Box 1)
    - 1977/1982 (Box 1)
      (draft, October, 1976)
    - 1977/1982 (Box 1)
      (draft, November, 1976)
    - 1977-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1978/1983 (Box 1)
      (draft, October, 1977)
    - 1978/1983 (Box 1)
      (draft, December, 1977)
    - 1978-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1988 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1991 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1992 (Box 1)
    - 1990-1996 (Box 1)
    - 1991-1997 (Box 1)
    - 1997-2003 (Box 1)
  - Minutes (Box 1)
  - Publications 1956-1961, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Non-serial publications
  - 1956
    - Planning information brochure (Box 1)
  - 1960
    - Chapter 55 -- Zoning (Box 1)
      (proposed zoning chapter)
  - 1961
    - Population and housing: a report on population and housing based on the 1960 federal decennial census. (Box 1)
  - 1962
    - A guide to action: the Ann Arbor Central Area (Box 4)
      (outsize)
    - Land development regulations (Box 2)
      (General development plan, Part 3, chapter 2, section 1-3)
    - Report of commercial zoning and development in Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1963
    - Ann Arbor Metropolitan Area traffic study: tabulations and trip tables (Box 2)
    - Northeast area study (Box 2)
    - West Jackson, Liberty-Stadium-Virginia Park area study (Box 2)
  - 1964
    - Planning Commission function and responsibility (Box 2)
  - 1965
    - Economic base report (Box 2)
    - Land development regulations, amended (Box 2)
      (General development plan, Part III, Chapter 2, Section 1-3)
    - Master plan profile: City of Ann Arbor Michigan general development plan, a descriptive summary (Box 2)
    - Plan for parks and open space (Box 4)
      (General development plan, Part 2, chapter 2)
    - R4 multiple family density study (Box 2)
  - 1966
    - Planned unit development study (Box 2)
      (Preliminary)
    - Plymouth Road density potential study (Box 2)
  - 1967
    - Economic base: a working paper (Box 2)
    - Industrial survey: factors affecting location-relocation patterns of manufacturing-research firms in the Ann Arbor area: a working paper (Box 2)
    - R4 multiple family density study: revised copy (Box 2)
  - 1968
    - State St. mall evaluation (Box 2)
    - Urban design for Ann Arbor (Box 2)
      (a general development plan working paper, February 1968)
    - Urban design for Ann Arbor (Box 2)
      (no date)
  - 1969
    - A guide for change: policies for public and private action
      - Preliminary: for citizen review and discussion (Box 4)
      - Second draft (outsize) (Box 4)
  - 1970
    - Design review (Box 2)
    - Land development regulations supplement (Box 2)
      (General development plan, March 1970)
  - 1971
    - Briarwood Shopping Center: a comprehensive report (Box 2)
    - A guide for change (Box 2)
    - Guide for change (Box 2)
      (summary)
    - Land development manual (Box 2)
      (Part II, first draft)
    - R2B district study (Box 2)
    - Zoning chapter amendments: townhouse and multi-family zones (Box 2)
  - 1972
    - The Ann Arbor growth study (Box 4)
    - General characteristics of population and housing
      - March 1972 (Box 2)
      - December 1972 (Box 2)
  - 1973
    - Central area policy plan for the city of Ann Arbor
      - June 1973 (Box 2)
      - June 1973 as amended July 24, 1973 (Box 2)
    - General development plan for the city of Ann Arbor
      - June 1973 (Box 2)
      - July 1973 (Box 2)
    - Land development manual (Box 2)
      (Part I and IV, first drafts, Part II, Chapters 1-5, revised)
    - Pittsfield Valley south area plan (Box 2)
  - 1974
    - Ann Arbor City Planning Commission: Organization, duties, policies, procedures, by-laws (Box 2)
    - Central area inventory report for the city of Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1975
    - Ann Arbor Municipal Airport, Master Plan Phase I (Box 3)
    - Downtown Ann Arbor: a development and conservation strategy (Box 3)
      (Central area plan, Part 1)
      (Draft)
    - Downtown Ann Arbor: a development and conservation strategy (Box 3)
    - Downtown concept plan (Box 3)
      (Draft 2, summary)
    - Zoning chapter revision working papers (Box 3)
  - 1976
    - Circulation plan elements (Box 3)
      (Circulation plan, Section 3)
      (Draft 1 of parts 2-4, 6-7)
    - Commercial zoning (Box 3)
      (Working paper, 4)
    - Compendium of south area plans and policies: core planning districts (Box 3)
    - Downtown Ann Arbor summary: development and conservation strategy (Box 3)
    - Downtown zoning (Box 3)
      (Working paper, 6)
    - Land use (Box 3)
      (Central neighborhood plan working paper, 1)
  - 1977
    - Circulation problem solving process (Box 3)
      (5th draft)
    - The downtown and close-in neighborhoods: that uneasy feeling (Box 3)
      (Central neighborhood plan working paper, 4)
    - Downtown Ann Arbor: a conservation and development strategy (Box 3)
      (Reprinted)
    - Housing (Central neighborhood plan working paper, 2) (Box 3)
    - Neighborhood livability and streets (Box 3)
      (Central neighborhood plan working paper, 3)
    - Plan for solving circulation problems (Box 3)
    - Proposed 1990 circulation plan (Box 3)
      (4th draft)
  - 1978
    - Proposed parks and open space plan (Box 3)
    - Vacant land inventory (Box 3)
  - 1980
    - Analysis of planning options and recommendations: a study of transitional and vacant land areas in Ann Arbor (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor household survey, supplemental tables (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor's housing supply and household characteristics (Box 3)
    - Planning options for Ann Arbor: a preliminary paper on land use options for transitional and vacant land areas (Box 3)
  - 1981
    - Ann Arbor community natural features inventory (Box 5)
    - Ann Arbor's park, recreation and open space plan
      - Preliminary draft February 1981 (Box 5)
      - Final draft June 1981 (Box 5)
    - Plan for transitional and vacant land areas (Box 5)
    - Zoning chapter revisions (Box 5)
  - 1983
    - The Ann Arbor corridor study: design guidelines for major roadways, Ann Arbor, Michigan (Box 5)
      (Summary report)
    - Ann Arbor downtown data: block data (Box 5)
    - Ann Arbor downtown data: establishment file (Box 5)
  - 1987
    - Ann Arbor's plan for parks, recreation and open space, 1988-1994 (Box 5)
      (Preliminary draft)
  - 1988
    - Ann Arbor downtown plan (Box 5)
    - Ann Arbor downtown plan: appendixes (Box 5)
    - Ann Arbor downtown plan: final draft summary (Box 5)
    - Ann Arbor downtown plan: final report summary (Box 5)
  - 1989
    - Northeast area plan for the city of Ann Arbor (Box 5)
  - 1990
    - Ann Arbor transportation plan update (Box 5)
  - 1992
    - Central area plan (Box 5)
    - Central area plan summary (Box 5)
  - Date unknown
    - Informational booklet, proposed north central urban renewal project, Ann Arbor, Michigan (Box 5)